A Finding Aid to the Gloria Ross Papers, circa 1924-1998, in the Archives of American Art AAA.rossglor
Archives of American Art
Gloria Ross papers
circa 1924-1998
AAA.rossglor
Archives of American Art
14 Linear feet
The papers of New York tapestry éditeur Gloria Ross measure 14.0 linear feet and date from circa 1924-1998. The bulk of the papers consist of project files that document her collaborations with artists to make tapestries of their paintings and collages. Also found are scattered biographical material, professional correspondence, exhibition files, professional activity files, personal business records, printed material, photographs, and artwork.
Ross, Gloria F.
Conditions Governing Access note
Use of original papers requires an appointment. Use of archival audiovisual recordings with no duplicate access copy requires advance notice.
Immediate Source of Acquisition note
Donated in 2013 by the Gloria Ross estate via Michael I. Katz, executor, with assistance from the Gloria F. Ross Tapestry Program, University of Arizona, via Ann Lane Hedlund, director.
Biographical/Historical note
Gloria F. Ross (1923-1998) was a tapestry éditeur in New York, New York.
Ross was born Gloria Frankenthaler in New York in 1923. She graduated from Mount Holyoke College in 1943 and married Alfred Ross. They had three children: Alfred, Beverly, and Clifford. In 1954, Gloria Ross made her first needlepoint work from a design by her sister, abstract painter Helen Frankenthaler, and by the mid-1960s, she was exhibiting her tapestries and hooked rugs in New York. She established Gloria F. Ross Studio in 1966 and began regularly collaborating with artists such as Robert Motherwell, Louise Nevelson, Jack Youngerman, and Jean Dubuffet to make their works into tapestries. She created business partnerships with weaving workshops in Scotland and France to produce the works. In 1973 she had her first exhibition at Pace Editions, Inc., beginning a long relationship with the gallery as her main sales agent.
In 1979, Ross first traveled to the Navajo Nation to find weavers for a collaborative project with artist Kenneth Noland. She continued to visit the Southwest at least once a year until 1994, and she donated her collection of Navajo rugs and other textiles to the Denver Art Museum. Throughout the 1980s Ross traveled extensively for projects, exhibitions, and symposia. Her final commissioned project, completed in 1997, was a tapestry designed by artist Mark Podwol for Temple Emanu-El in New York. That same year she established the Gloria F. Ross Center for Tapestry Studies in Tucson, Arizona.
Scope and Contents note
The papers of New York tapestry éditeur Gloria Ross measure 14.0 linear feet and date from circa 1924-1998. The bulk of the papers consist of project files that document her collaborations with artists to make tapestries of their paintings and collages. Also found are scattered biographical material, professional correspondence, exhibition files, professional activity files, personal business records, printed material, photographs, and artwork.
Biographical material includes resumes and career summaries, as well as an interview of Ross on one videocassette, and a few Frankenthaler family documents. Correspondence is with artists, weavers, workshops, publications, and galleries and is of a professional nature.
Project files document Ross's collaborations with prominent artists such as Helen Frankenthaler, Robert Motherwell, Romare Bearden, Louise Nevelson, Milton Avery, Stuart Davis, and others. Project files may include correspondence, contracts, invoices, notes, photographs, yarn samples, and a few maquettes and cartoons. Also of note are extensive files regarding her collaborations with Navajo weavers to create tapestries based on geometric paintings by Kenneth Noland. Other project files include a commissioned tapestry for Temple Emanu-El in New York.
Exhibition files document various solo and group exhibitions of Gloria Ross tapestries and includes one videocassette from a 1978 exhibition. Records of her professional activities include her participation in symposia, lectures, and public events. Files may include correspondence, draft lectures, programs, and event publicity. Two short documentaries found on two videocassettes were produced for the Denver Art Museum. Personal business records document Ross's business relationships with weaving workshops and art galleries, most notably Atelier Raymond Picaud, Pinton atelier, Edinburgh Tapestry Company (Dovecot Studios), and Pace Editions, the major sales agent of Gloria Ross tapestries.
Printed material consists of catalogs, announcements, press releases, and other publications regarding exhibitions of Gloria Ross tapestries and Navajo tapestries. Photographs depict Ross, the Frankenthaler family, Ross's tapestries, weaving studios, and Navajo weavers. Artwork includes one painting by Paul Jenkins and unidentified textile and yarn samples.
Arrangement note
This collection is arranged as 9 series.
Series 1: Biographical Material, circa 1926-1998 (5 folders; Box 1)
Series 2: Correspondence, 1965-1998 (0.7 linear feet; Box 1)
Series 3: Project Files, 1960-1998 (7.3 linear feet; Boxes 1-7, 14-15, 17-19, OVs 20, 22-24, Artifact)
Series 4: Exhibition Files, 1967-1994 (0.8 linear feet; Boxes 7-8, 17)
Series 5: Professional Activities, 1955-1997 (0.7 linear feet; Box 8)
Series 6: Personal Business Records, 1964-1998 (1.8 linear feet; Boxes 8-10, OV 21)
Series 7: Printed Material, 1970s-1990s (0.8 linear feet; Boxes 10-11, 14)
Series 8: Photographs, circa 1924-1990s (1.1 linear feet; Boxes 11, 16)
Series 9: Artwork, circa 1970s-1990s (1.1 linear feet; Boxes 11-14, 17, 19)
Atelier Raymond Picaud.; Avery, Milton, 1885-1965; Bearden, Romare, 1911-1988; Davis, Stuart, 1892-1964; Denver Art Museum.; Dovecot Studios.; Frankenthaler, Helen, 1928-2011; Motherwell, Robert; Nevelson, Louise, 1899-1988; Noland, Kenneth, 1924-; Pace Editions. (Firm); Pinton Atelier.; Temple Emanu-El. (Bayonne, N.J.); Designers--New York (State)--New York; Interviews; Navajo weavers; Paintings; Photographs; Tapestry--Design; Tapestry--Production control; Tapestry--Technique; Video recordings; Women artists--New York (State)--New York
- Biographical Material, circa 1926-1998; Series 1; 5 Folders Box 1
  Scope and Contents note
  A small amount of biographical material on Gloria Ross includes resumes, Who's Who biographies, career summaries, a high school yearbook, and her college diploma. Also found is one videocassette containing a television interview. Family records primarily consist of news clippings about Ross's father, Alfred Frankenthaler.
  - Biographical Summaries, circa 1970s-1990s (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Dallas Television Interview, 1979; 1 Videocassettes (Betamax) (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Frankenthaler Family, circa 1926-1928; 1958 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Horace Mann School for Girls, 1940 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Mount Holyoke College, 1944; 1998 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Correspondence, 1965-1998; Series 2; 0.7 Linear feet Box 1
  Correspondence is with artists, weavers, workshops, publications, and galleries. Contents are primarily of a professional nature discussing tapestry commissions and sales, artist collaborations, exhibitions. Subject matter may directly relate to correspondence found within project files, exhibition files, and personal business records. Some of the correspondence is in French.
  Arrangement note
  Correspondence is arranged chronologically.
  - Correspondence, 1965-1969 (Box 1, Folder 6-8)
  - Correspondence, 1970-1978 (Box 1, Folder 9-12)
  - Correspondence, 1979-1988 (Box 1, Folder 13-18)
  - Correspondence, 1989-1998 (Box 1, Folder 19-26)
- Project Files, 1960-1998; Series 3; 7.3 Linear feet Boxes 1-7, 14-15, 17-19, OVs 20, 22-24, Artifact
  Project files primarily document Ross's collaborations with prominent artists to create tapestries of their paintings. She worked with artists such as Helen Frankenthaler, Robert Motherwell, Romare Bearden, Louise Nevelson, Milton Avery, and Stuart Davis to create designs and selected weavers to translate the artworks into tapestries. She also oversaw commissions and sales of these works to individuals, corporations, and museums. Project files may include correspondence, contracts, invoices, notes, photographs, yarn samples, and a few maquettes and cartoons. Also of note are extensive files regarding her collaborations with Kenneth Noland, with whom she had the longest working relationship of any artist. Included is documentation regarding the Native/Noland series. For this series Ross worked with Navajo weavers to create tapestries based on Noland's geometric paintings. Researchers should note that a few files document project collaborations that were never realized.
  Other project files found here include a commissioned tapestry for Temple Emanu-El in collaboration with artist Mark Podwal, as well as commissions for Mazza Gallerie, Phoenix Civic Center, and Westinghouse Broadcasting Company. Documents include correspondence, invoices, agreements, photographs, and notes. Files regarding a Vesti Corporation mostly contain legal records and correspondence regarding Gloria Ross's role in the project.
  This series is arranged as 2 subseries.
  3.1: Artist Collaborations, 1960-1998
  3.2: Other Projects, 1971-1997
  - Artist Collaborations, 1960-1998; 3.1
    - Anuszkiewicz, Richard, circa 1971-1979 (Box 1, Folder 27-30)
    - Avery, Milton, 1973-1993 (Box 2, Folder 1-7)
      Oversized material housed in Box 17
    - Bearden, Romare, 1974-1997 (Box 2, Folder 8-12)
      Oversized material housed in Box 19
    - Bill, Max, 1971-1977 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Calder, Alexander, 1976-1994 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Cosindas, Marie, 1966-1979 (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Davis, Gene, 1972-1973 (Box 2, Folder 16-17)
    - Davis, Stuart, 1987-1995 (Box 2, Folder 18-24)
      Oversized material housed in Box 14
    - Downing, Thomas, circa 1970 (Box 2, Folder 25)
    - Dubuffet, Jean, 1973-1995 (Box 2, Folder 26-27)
    - Dubuffet, Jean, 1973-1995 (Box 3, Folder 1-2)
    - Dufy, Raoul, 1992-1993 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Erte, 1975-1983 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Feeley, Paul, 1966-1971 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Frankenthaler, Helen, Fourth National Bank and Trust Commission, 1973-1975 (Box 3, Folder 6-9)
      Oversized material housed in Box 15
    - Frankenthaler, Helen, Halperin Commission, 1969-1972 (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - Frankenthaler, Helen, Southeast Banking Corporation Commission, 1982-1983 (Box 3, Folder 11-12)
    - Frankenthaler, Helen, Winters Bank Tower Commission, 1971-1972 (Box 3, Folder 13-15)
    - Frankenthaler, Helen, 1966-1998 (Box 3, Folder 16-22)
    - Goodnough, Robert, 1967-1991 (Box 4, Folder 1-2)
      Oversized material housed in Boxes 17 and 19
    - Gottlieb, Adolph, 1970-circa 1976 (Box 4, Folder 3-6)
      Oversized material housed in Box 17 and OV 23
    - Gray, Eileen, 1979-1980 (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Held, Al, 1968-1975 (Box 4, Folder 8-10)
    - Hofmann, Hans, 1976-1995 (Box 4, Folder 11-13)
    - Jenkins, Paul, 1973-1982 (Box 4, Folder 14-17)
    - Kelly, Ellsworth, 1965; 1972 (Box 4, Folder 18)
    - Lawrence, Jacob, 1990-1994 (Box 4, Folder 19)
    - Liberman, Alexander, 1974-1976 (Box 4, Folder 20)
    - Lichtenstein, Roy, 1980 (Box 4, Folder 21)
    - Lidner, Richard, 1973-1974 (Box 4, Folder 22-23)
    - Louis, Morris, 1970-1971 (Box 4, Folder 24)
    - Marca-Relli, Conrad, 1970-1983 (Box 4, Folder 25)
    - Moore, Henry, 1972-1973 (Box 4, Folder 26)
    - Motherwell, Robert, 1960-1993 (Box 4, Folder 27-33)
      Oversized material housed in Box 18
    - Nevelson, Louise, circa 1972-1980 (Box 4, Folder 34-35)
    - Nevelson, Louise, 1976-1998 (Box 5, Folder 1-5)
      Oversized material housed in Box 14, 18, and OV 22
    - Noland, Kenneth, 1967-1997 (Box 5, Folder 5-13)
      Oversized material housed in OV 20
    - Noland, Kenneth, Native/Noland Tapestries, 1979-1997 (Box 5, Folder 14-34)
    - Noland, Kenneth, Native/Noland Tapestries, 1980-1996 (Box 6, Folder 1-4)
    - O'Keeffe, Georgia, 1970-1978 (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Poons, Larry, 1970-1971 (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Ross, Clifford, 1974-1979 (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - Samaras, Lucas, 1974-1975 (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - Smith, Richard, 1967-1992 (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - Stella, Frank, 1972-1990 (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - Trova, Ernest, 1972-1993 (Box 6, Folder 11-12)
    - Youngerman, Jack, 1968-1997 (Box 6, Folder 13-19)
      Oversized material housed in Boxes 17, 19, OV 23, and OV 24
    - Youngerman, Jack, Portland Court House, circa 1976 (Box 6, Folder 20-22)
    - Oversized, Davis, Stuart from Box 2, Folders 18-24, circa 1970s (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - Oversized, Dubuffet, Jean from Box 3, Folders 1-2, 1973 (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - Oversized, Liberman, Alexander from Box 4, Folder 20, circa 1974 (Box 14, Folder 3)
    - Oversized, Marca-Relli, Conrad from Box 4, Folder 25, 1970s (Box 14, Folder 4)
    - Oversized, Nevelson, Louise from Box 5, Folders 1-5, circa 1970s-1980s (Box 14, Folder 5)
    - Oversized, Frankenthaler, Helen, Fourth National Bank and Trust Commission from Box 3, Folders 6-9, circa 1973 (Box 15, Folder 1)
    - Oversized, Frankenthaler, Helen from Box 3, Folder 16-22, circa 1969-1980s (Box 15, Folder 2-4)
    - Oversized, Avery, Milton from Box 2, Folders 1-7, circa 1970s (Box 17, Folder 1)
    - Oversized, Goodnough, Robert from Box 4, Folders 1-2, circa 1970s (Box 17, Folder 2)
    - Oversized, Gottlieb, Adolph from Box 4, Folders 3-6, circa 1970s (Box 17, Folder 3)
    - Oversized, Trova, Ernest from Box 6, Folders 11-12, circa 1970s (Box 17, Folder 4)
    - Oversized, Youngerman, Jack from Box 6, Folders 13-19, circa 1970s (Box 17, Folder 5)
    - Oversized, Motherwell, Robert from Box 4, Folders 27-33, circa 1970s (Box 18)
    - Oversized, Nevelson, Louise from Box 5, Folders 1-5, circa 1970s (Box 18)
    - Oversized, Bearden, Romare from Box 2, Folders 8-12, circa 1970s (Box 19)
    - Oversized, Goodnough, Robert from Box 4, Folders 1-2, circa 1970s (Box 19)
    - Oversized, Youngerman, Jack from Box 6, Folders 13-19, circa 1970s (Box 19)
    - Oversized, Noland, Kenneth from Box 5, Folders 5-13, circa 1970s (Box OV 20)
    - Oversized, Nevelson, Louise from Box 5, Folders 1-5, circa 1970s (Box OV 22)
    - Oversized, Gottlieb, Adolph from Box 4, Folders 3-6, circa 1970s (Box OV 23)
    - Oversized, Youngerman, Jack from Box 6, Folders 13-19, circa 1970s (Box OV 23)
    - Oversized, Youngerman, Jack from Box 6, Folders 13-19, circa 1970s (Box OV 24)
  - Other Projects, 1971-1997; 3.2
    - Congregation Emanu-El, 1994-1997 (Box 6, Folder 23-29)
    - Mazza Gallerie, Prudential Insurance Company, 1984-1986 (Box 7, Folder 1-2)
    - Phoenix Civic Center, 1986-1988 (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - Vesti Corporation, KAIA Project, 1980-1982 (Box 7, Folder 4-5)
    - Westinghouse Broadcasting Company, 1971-1973 (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - Oversized, Congregation Emanu-El from Box 6, Folders 23-29, circa 1990s (Box 14, Folder 6)
- Exhibition Files, 1967-1994; Series 4; 0.8 Linear feet Boxes 7-8, 17
  Exhibition files document various solo and group exhibitions of Gloria Ross tapestries. Files may include correspondence, planning documents, loan forms, lists of works, press clippings, exhibition catalogs, and photographs. Also included are records of the exhibition "Navajo Weavings: State of the Art," curated by Ross at Kauffman Galleries. One videocassette documents an unspecified exhibition of Gloria Ross tapestries. Researchers should note that additional documentation on exhibitions may be found in Series 2: Correspondence.
  - Richard Feigen Gallery, "Gloria F. Ross" (1969) (Box 7, Folder 7-8)
  - Richard Feigen Gallery, "Tapestries by Gloria F. Ross" (1971), 1970-1971 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Pyramid Galleries, "Gloria F. Ross Tapestries" (1972) (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Pace Gallery, "Tapestries" (1975), circa 1975 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - International Biennial of Tapestry, Lausanne (1977), 1976-1978 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - New Gallery of Contemporary Art, "Gloria F. Ross Tapestries" (1977) (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Kauffman Fine Art, "Tapestry" (1977), 1977-1982 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Jacksonville Art Museum, "Tapestries and Banners" (1977) (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Unidentified Venue, "Gloria Ross Tapestries Exhibit", circa 1978; 1 Videocassettes (U-matic) (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - J. Walter Thompson, "Gloria F. Ross Contemporary Tapestries" (1978) (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - Ringling Museum of Art, "Contemporary Tapestries" (1978), 1977-1978 (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - Nabisco, Inc., "Contemporary Tapestries" (1978) (Box 7, Folder 19)
  - NorthPark National Bank, "Gloria F. Ross Tapestries" (1979), 1978-1979 (Box 7, Folder 20)
  - Mount Holyoke College Art Museum, "Gloria F. Ross Tapestries" (1979), 1978-1979 (Box 7, Folder 21)
  - Thomas Segal Gallery, "Paper, Clay, and Tapestry" (1979), 1978-1979 (Box 7, Folder 22)
  - William A. Farnsworth Library and Art Museum, "The Art of Louise Nevelson" (1979-1980) (Box 7, Folder 23)
  - FIAC80, Paris (1980) (Box 7, Folder 24)
  - Scottish Arts Council, "Master Weavers: Tapestry from the Dovecot Studios" (1980-1981) (Box 7, Folder 25-26)
  - Kauffman Galleries, "Navajo Weaving: State of the Art" (1983), 1982-1983 (Box 7, Folder 27)
  - Cheney Cowles Memorial Museum, "Tapestry: Contemporary Imagery Ancient Tradition" (1986), 1985-1986 (Box 7, Folder 28)
  - Rutgers Barclay Gallery, "Tapestries" (1989), 1988-1989 (Box 7, Folder 29-30)
  - Centre International De L'Architecture Tissee, "D'Artistes Americains Contemporains" (1990), circa 1990 (Box 7, Folder 31)
  - Group Shows, 1967-1988 (Box 7, Folder 32-33)
  - Various Exhibitions on Stuart Davis, 1989-1994 (Box 8, Folder 1-2)
  - Oversized, Mount Holyoke College Art Museum from Box 7, Folder 21, 1978-1979 (Box 17, Folder 6)
- Professional Activities, 1955-1997; Series 5; 0.7 Linear feet Box 8
  Found here are records of Gloria Ross's professional activities, including her participation in symposia, lectures, public events, and documentary film projects. Files may include correspondence, draft lectures, programs, and event publicity. Two short documentaries found on two videocassettes were produced for the Denver Art Museum. Also found are records of Ross's service on the board of the Textile Museum. Additionally there are subject files that Ross maintained regarding various artists, weavers, and tapestry workshops, which include correspondence, photographs of artwork, publications, and lists.
  - Artists, 1985-1993 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Board Member, Child Development Center, 1955-1972 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Board Member, Textile Museum, 1992-1997 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Documentary, "Weavers", 1992; 1 Videocassettes (VHS) (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Documentary, "Weave of Life", 1992; 1 Videocassettes (VHS) (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Lecture, Asia Society, 1992 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Lecture, Yale Club, 1991-1992 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Symposium, University of Maryland, 1988-1989 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Symposium, Victorian Tapestry Workshop, 1987-1988 (Box 8, Folder 11-12)
  - Talks and Events, Miscellaneous, 1973-1991 (Box 8, Folder 13-15)
  - Weavers and Workshops, Archie Brennan, 1987-1991 (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - Weavers and Workshops, Sheila Hicks, 1978-1980 (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - Weavers and Workshops, Ramona Sakiestewa, 1983-1994 (Box 8, Folder 18)
  - Weavers and Workshops, "Durango Collection", circa 1990s; 1 Videocassettes (VHS) (Box 8, Folder 19)
  - Weavers and Workshops, International, 1972-1993 (Box 8, Folder 20)
  - Weavers and Workshops, Miscellaneous, circa 1982-1994 (Box 8, Folder 21-22)
- Personal Business Records, 1964-1998; Series 6; 1.8 Linear feet Boxes 8-10, OV 21
  Personal business records primarily document Ross's business relationships with weaving workshops and art galleries. Included are extensive correspondence, agreements, and financial documents from Atelier Raymond Picaud, Pinton atelier, and Edinburgh Tapestry Company (Dovecot Studios). Also found are extensive records with Pace Editions, the major sales agent of Gloria Ross tapestries. Other records include commission ideas, inventories of works, sales records, and travel documents. Also of note is business correspondence with tapestry producer Yvette Conquil-Prince. Researchers should note that much of the documentation in this series is in French.
  - Atelier Raymond Picaud, 1972-1975 (Box 8, Folder 23-25)
  - Bills and Receipts, 1964-1978 (Box 8, Folder 26-27)
  - Business Cards and Addresses, circa 1970s-1990s (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Cauquil-Prince, Yvette, 1973-1985 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Commission Notes and Ideas, 1965-1970s (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Contract Forms, circa 1960s-1980s (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Edinburgh Tapestry Company (Dovecot), circa 1969-1988 (Box 9, Folder 5-9)
  - Galleries, Miscellaneous, 1980-1982 (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Gallery 10, 1980-1997 (Box 9, Folder 11-12)
  - Gallery Urban, 1990-1991 (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - Handarbetets vanner, 1975-1976 (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - Hokin Gallery, 1978-1988 (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - Hooberman Gallery, 1981-1982 (Box 9, Folder 16)
  - Inventory of Materials, circa 1970s (Box 9, Folder 17)
  - Kennedy Tapestries, 1981-1988 (Box 9, Folder 18)
  - Le Corbusier and Leger Tapestries, circa 1984-1994 (Box 9, Folder 19)
  - Manufactura De Tapecarias De Portalegre, 1970-1974 (Box 9, Folder 20)
  - Marjory Jacobson Fine Arts Planning Group, 1982-1986 (Box 9, Folder 21)
  - Navajo Rugs, 1992-1993 (Box 9, Folder 22)
  - Pace Editions, Inc., 1972-1995 (Box 9, Folder 23-25)
    Oversized poster housed in OV 21
  - Pinton, 1971-1988 (Box 9, Folder 26-33)
  - Pinton, 1989-1998 (Box 10, Folder 1-5)
  - PR Past and for Future, 1972-1985 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Price Lists, circa 1990s (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Sales, Frank Guidara, 1988 (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Scheuer Tapestry Studio, 1984-1987 (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Stephanie Mallis, Inc., 1992-1993 (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Tapestry Dealers, 1971-1997 (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - Tapestry Workshops, France, circa 1970-1979 (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - Travel Documents, 1988-1989 (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - Unpriced Inventory, circa 1990s (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - Victorian Tapestry Workshop, 1981-1988 (Box 10, Folder 15)
  - Address Card File, circa 1970s-1990s (Box 10, Folder 16)
  - Oversized Pace Editions, Inc. Poster from Box 9, Folders 23-25, 1972 (Box OV 21)
- Printed Material, 1970s-1990s; Series 7; 0.8 Linear feet Boxes 10-11, 14
  Printed material includes exhibition catalogs, announcements, posters, and press releases, as well as news clippings regarding exhibitions of Gloria Ross tapestries and Navajo tapestries. Also found are a few newsletters and bulletins from art museums.
  - Auction Catalog, 1997 (Box 10, Folder 17)
  - Book, Reflections of the Weaver's World, 1992 (Box 10, Folder 18)
  - Exhibition Announcements and Catalogs, 1970s-1990s (Box 10, Folder 19-20)
  - News Clippings, circa 1970s-1990s (Box 11, Folder 1-2)
  - Newsletters and Bulletins, 1979-1992 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Postcards (Blank), circa 1970s (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Posters, 1972 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Press Releases, circa 1970s-1980s (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Oversized News Clippings from Box 11, Folders 1-2, 1970s-1980s (Box 14, Folder 7)
- Photographs, circa 1924-1990s; Series 8; 1.1 Linear feet Boxes 11, 16
  Personal photographs of Gloria Ross depict her as a child, on her wedding day, at an event with Gerald Ford, and with her sister Helen Frankenthaler. Also found are numerous photographs and color transparencies of Gloria Ross tapestries, including a few installation views, and Navajo tapestries donated and exhibited at the Denver Art Museum. Additionally, there are many polaroids of Navajo weavers and their tapestries and weavers working at the Pinton Atelier and Edinburgh Tapestry Company.
  - Gloria Ross, 1946-1981 (Box 11, Folder 7)